Muhammad Islam Kamran

MPhil in Computer Science and Cryptography

Introduction

I have 2+ years of expertise am quite well in all facets of multimedia encryption and cryptography. I am skilled in development with MATLAB and security. Additionally, I'm looking for a company where I can use my experience and abilities to participate as a team member. I enjoy working in a security atmosphere since I am technical and rational.

Professional Experience

2020-2022 **Research Fellow**, *Quaid.i.Azam University*, Islamabad, Pakistan.

Working on building of new multimedia Image Encryption algorithm using Quantum computation algorithm.

2019-2020 Trainee, Flutter Application developer for Android and IOS, PureTech, Pvt. Ltd., Peshawar, Pakistan.

Education

2020-2022 MPhil, Quaid.i.Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan, CGPA - 3.7/4.00.

Computer Science and Cryptography (Multimedia Image Encryption, Quantum Computing, and Chaos)

2016-2020 **BS**, University of Engineering & Technology, Peshawar, Pakistan, CGPA - 3.32/4.00. Computer Systems Engineering (C/C++, Data Structure & Algorithms, Data Analytics, OOP, and Computer Security

Research Publications

Journals, Published.

1. Kamran, M. I., Khan, M. A., Alsuhibany, S. A., Ghadi, Y. Y., Arif, J., and Ahmad, J. "A Highly Secured Image Encryption Scheme Using Quantum Walk and Chaos." Computers Materials and Continua, 73(1), 2022 (SCI).

Projects

Image Encryption Using Quantum Walk Algorithm.

- Quantum Walk Algorithm
- Secure communication between different end nodes
- Secured delivery of sensitive Image data.
 - Duration: September(2021) May(2022)

Object Detection and Characterization of Traffic Using Live Video Stream With Machine Learning Algorithm Software.

- o A project for detecting number of vehicles and pedestrians on road and counting their number for traffic controlling.
 - Duration: September(2019) July(2020)

- Islamabad, Pakistan

inIslam Kamran

Human Face detection using Open-CV.

- A desktop application for detecting human faces.
 - Duration: September 2019 October 2019

Concept TV.

- Implemented a Trainee project at PureTech Pvt. Ltd in Dart(Flutter)
 - Duration: June 2019 September 2019

Areas Of Interest

- Computer Security
- Multimedia Encryption
- Cryptography
- MATLAB for Development

Awards and Distinctions

- Research Fellow funded at Quaid.i.Azam
 Awarded by Higher education commission University, Islamabad
- Department of Computer Systems Engineering, UET Peshawar, Pakistan
- HEC, Pakistan
- o Graduated among top 10 2020 batch at Ovice Chancellor Islamia College Peshawar topper of the year talent Award

Certifications

- 2019 MATLAB Onramp
- 2019 Microsoft Word
- 2018 Introduction to Packet tracer

Academic Skills

Theoretical knowledge and competences.

I have gained a solid understanding of ideas related to computer security, encryption algorithms, quantum computing algorithms, and security of multimedia during my research fellowship.

Encryption Tools and Algorithms.

- AES
- DES
- Quantum Walk
- Multimedia Encryption

- XORing
- Chaos
- Logistic Maps
- MATLAB

Programming Skills: .

C, C++, MATLAB, System Programming, OOP, Flutter, Verilog HDL

Organisational Skills and Competences

Lead 2 projects under supervision of Prof. Dr. Muazzam Ali Khan Khattak and Prof. Dr. Nasru Minallah, I can operate under pressure and meet deadlines because I have leadership skills. I am aware that being provoked by peers and inferiors will not make me angry.

Social Skills

Being good at meeting new acquaintances, adjusting to new teammates while studying in a multi ethnic setting, and interacting with people from various cultures and ethnicities

Languages

English: Official/Academic Language
Urdu: National/Official Language
(Advanced level speaking, reading and writing skills)

Pashto: Native Language
(Advanced level speaking, reading and writing skills)

(Advanced level speaking, reading skills)

(Advanced level speaking, reading skills)

(Limited Speaking level, good understanding level skills)

References

Prof. Dr. Muazzam Ali Khan Khattak,

- Faculty, Quaid.i.Azam University, Islamabad and Adjunct Graduate Faculty, UMKC ,
- Email: muazzam.khattak@qau.edu.pk

Associate Prof. Dr. Rabeeh Ayaz Abbasi,

- HOD, Department of Computer Science, Quaid.i.Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan,
- Email: rabbasi@qau.edu.pk

Prof. Laiq Hasan,

- Faculty, Department of Computer System Engineering, University of Engineering and Technology, Peshawar, Pakistan,
- Email: laiqhasan@gmail.com